nursezone.com 2013-11-26

# Privacy Policy - NurseZone

##### Who We Are

NurseZone.com is a health care information and career portal on the Internet that is dedicated to nurses. We also publish _NurseZone_ , the magazine. NurseZone is a division of AMN Healthcare, which is the largest temporary health care staffing organization in the United States. You can learn more about AMN Healthcare by clicking on [www.amnhealthcare.com](http://www.amnhealthcare.com/ "www.amnhealthcare.com").

##### How to Reach Us

General mailing address:

NurseZone.com  
12400 High Bluff Drive  
San Diego, California 92130  
USA

Toll-free telephone number: (877) 585-5010

E-mail address for privacy issues: [contact@nursezone.com](mailto:%20contact@nursezone.com "contact@nursezone.com")

##### What Information You Provide and How it is Used

NurseZone may collect certain information from you. Please be assured that your privacy is protected and is safeguarded in the following ways:

  * We will not disclose your social security number or any other personal information you provide to us unless you authorize us to do so, except where needed to deliver a service or product ordered by you or under the limited circumstances set forth below.  
  * Please be advised that we may share your personal information with our parent company or affiliated divisions/companies, which may contact you regarding recruitment opportunities.  
  * We will always give you the opportunity to access and correct your personal information at any time.
  * We will not disclose your application status without your authorization.

##### When and How Your Personal Information is Provided

There are various areas on the NurseZone site where we either require or permit you to transfer personal information voluntarily. We never divulge such information to third parties without your consent. These areas include:

 _E-commerce._ We do not offer merchandise for sale to our users online. However, we have third party relationships with a select group of online stores. You may shop at these stores by using a link from our site to theirs. These third parties may request and record information about your purchases such as your address and credit card information. We cannot guarantee your privacy on third party Web sites and do not have control over their privacy policies or content. We urge you to review the privacy policy of any third party provider and determine how your personal information will be used prior to making a purchase. Your correspondence or business dealings with any third party providers, including payment and delivery of goods or services, and any other terms, conditions, warranties or representations associated with such dealings are solely between you and such providers.

 _Registration for Continuing Education Courses._ NurseZone may host continuing education courses for our registered users online. Enrollment in these courses is optional and at your complete discretion. When you register for continuing education courses you will be required to provide billing information exactly as it appears on your credit card statement, so that we can process your order including your name, address, telephone number, credit card number and expiration date. The information you provide is used solely for the continuing education course purchased. We may record information about registration for continuing education courses to determine which courses appeal most to members of our group. This statistical information may help us to improve our product offerings.

In addition, we provide links to third party Web sites that offer continuing education courses on nursing and other health care related topics. Enrollment in such courses is completely optional and at your discretion. You should be aware that third party providers may request and record registration information about you. We cannot guarantee your privacy on third party Web sites and do not have control over their privacy policies or content. Review the privacy policy of any third party provider and determine how your personal information will be used prior to registering for a continuing education course. Your correspondence or business dealings with any third party providers, including payment and delivery of goods or services, and any other terms, conditions, warranties or representations associated with such dealings, are solely between you and such providers.

 _Job Center and Career Resources._ In order to use our career resources, which cover recruitment and placement of nurses, we require that you register with our site. We ask you to provide your name, e-mail address, nursing specialty or discipline and some other general information. In connection with our career services, we will offer you the opportunity to be contacted by one of our partners' career advisors. If you choose to be contacted, an advisor will contact you via your e-mail address, mailing address or telephone number. In addition, our site contains a "Résumé Creator" program which enables our registered users to create and print résumés and post them on our site.

Our site will enable the user to e-mail the résumé to us at NurseZone. You may forward the résumé via e-mail or facsimile to selected health care facilities or other organizations. In addition, each user who posts a résumé on our site will be assigned a unique URL number. Should a user provide the URL number to third parties other than NurseZone, we cannot guarantee your privacy. We urge you not to disclose your personal URL number to anyone.

 _Forums and Blogs._ We offer message forums and blogs that permit posting opportunities for our registered users. Please see our Terms of Use before using these features. Also, bulletin board messages posted by users may be featured in NurseZone's weekly e-newsletter.

 _Correspondence._ When you sign-up for our weekly e-mail newsletter, which contains a variety of information on nursing-related topics you, will be required to provide your name and e-mail address. Your name and e-mail address will not be shared with any third parties.

There may be other times when we request your e-mail address, such as when you send us an e-mail with questions or comments. We will use your e-mail address to respond to your questions or comments, send information concerning your account and inform you of updates to our Web site. We do not share e-mail addresses or any other personal information about our registered users with advertisers, business partners, sponsors or other third parties except to provide services you have requested.

 _Special Contests and Promotions._ NurseZone will occasionally feature a contest/promotion for nurses. In order to enter the contest/promotion, we require you to provide us with your name, phone number and e-mail address so that we can contact you if you win. We may also ask for other information that will help us reach nurses with our extensive site offerings. Your information will only be shared with third parties if you request to receive information from the provider parties.

 _Application Form._ NurseZone allows you to apply to its health care staffing partners by completing an online application form. Completion of this form is completely optional and at your discretion. Information that will be gathered by completing this form includes your name, address, age, social security number, dates available to work, certification, licensure, education, employment history, legal history and eligibility to work in the United States. The information you provide is used solely for the purpose of assessing your suitability to work as a health care traveler and to match your expertise with available travel assignments.

##### Information Independently Derived from Your Use of Our Site

Aside from any information you may actively disclose to us, there is other, less obvious, information which we might obtain from you. We may use this type of information for internal purposes such as to improve the content of our Web pages.

 _Cookies._ A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies are widely used on the Internet and are an industry standard. Cookies enable user registration and login and personalization, among other things. On our site you are required to accept a cookie when you log-in to use our bulletin board. The cookie is used to remind us of who you are. When you are logged into the bulletin board, the cookie permits you to click on to another site and return to the bulletin board without having to log-in again. Although a cookie cannot, in and of itself, identify you, it can identify your computer. Your browser is most likely set up to accept cookies automatically. If you would like to disable this feature you may do so by adjusting the options or preferences in your browser. However, by doing so, you will lose some of the convenience of our Web pages.

 _IP Addresses._ An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you begin service with an Internet Service Provider. We collect IP addresses for the purposes of system administration and to audit the use of our site. Each time you log onto our site and each time you request one of our pages, our server logs your IP address. Although we log your session with us, we will not normally link your IP address to anything that can enable us to identify you. However, we can and will use IP addresses to identify a user when we feel it is necessary to enforce compliance with our rules or terms of service or to protect our service, site, users or others.

 _Other Information._ NurseZone may require other information for tracking or verifying compliance with our policies, abiding by federal, state and local laws and for editorial and feedback solicitation purposes. In addition, from time to time, we may use your information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy policy. If our information practices materially change at some time in the future, we will contact you or post such change to the site before we use your data for these new purposes. If you are concerned about how your information is used, please periodically check our privacy policy.

##### How to Change Your User Information

You may update information related to your account or contact us with questions by sending an e-mail to us at [contact@nursezone.com.](mailto:%20contact@nursezone.com "contact@nursezone.com.") 

##### When We May Be Forced to Disclose

We may disclose user information in special cases when we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) our rights or property or the rights or property of our users or others. We also may disclose user information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.

##### Opting-Out

If at any time you object to our use of your personal information, including use of your e-mail address, you may request to be removed from our list. Send your opt-out request by e-mail to [contact@nursezone.com](mailto:%20contact@nursezone.com "contact@nursezone.com").

##### NurseJobs iphone Mobile Application:

In addition to information collected on the NurseZone.com Web site, NurseZone sponsors the NurseJobs iphone Mobile Application, which is available for free download on iTunes or by visiting the NurseZone Web site: <http://www.nursezone.com/social-media/iphone.aspx> 

The NurseJobs application allows you to search jobs and view videos and news provided by NurseZone.com. While using the NurseJobs application, you may be interested in information about jobs provided on the NurseJobs application. If interseted, you are requested to provide your name, e-mail address, nursing specialty or discipline and some other general information. In connection with our career services, we will offer you the opportunity to be contacted by one of our partners' career advisors at American Mobile Healthcare, NursesRx, Medical Express, NurseChoice or Nursefinders. If you choose to be contacted, an advisor will contact you via your e-mail address, mailing address or telephone number. These partners are also owned and operated by AMN Healthcare and follow the same stringent privacy guidelines as NurseZone.com. Should you wish to have your information removed from our database or the database of our partners after submitting a contact form on the NurseJobs iphone application, please email us at [contact@nursezone.com](mailto:contact@nursezone.com).  

##### Links to Other Sites

Linking to other sites is an integral part of the functionality of the Internet and our site. Any link to a page which displays a URL of a non-NurseZone site in the address window of your browser or which indicates that it is "powered by" an entity other than NurseZone, is a link to a site outside of our service. This includes links to any advertisers and partners that may link to NurseZone or are part of a co-branding or partnership agreement, as well as other suggested links or links our users may post. These other sites may send their own cookies to you, collect data or solicit personal information. Please note that we cannot guarantee and are not responsible for the content of outside sites.

Please keep in mind that whenever you give out personal information on other Web sites that information can be collected and used by people you do not know. While we strive to protect our visitors' personal information and privacy, we cannot guarantee the security and privacy of any information you disclose at other Web sites, and you do so at your own risk.

##### Security

The importance of security is a top priority for us. We exercise great care in providing secure transmission of your information from your Internet connection to our servers. We also take great care to protect users' information off-line. All of your data is handled only by authorized personnel and our database servers have a backup system to prevent loss of data. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100 percent secure and we will not be held liable should a third party illegally obtain your personal information. While we have made a great effort to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk.

Our policy does not extend to anything that is inherent in the operation of the Internet, and therefore beyond our control, and is not to be applied in any manner contrary to applicable law or governmental regulation.

##### Your Acceptance of These Terms

By using this site, you signify your consent to the NurseZone privacy policy and the terms of use. If you do not agree with this policy and these terms, please refrain from using our site. Notice of any changes to our privacy policy will be posted on this site. Your continued use of the NurseZone site following a reasonable notice of changes to our privacy policy or terms of use will mean you accept the changes.

###### _NurseZone's_ privacy policy is effective as of March 12, 2004. The policy was last updated as of December 31, 2012.
